JANNATUL FERDOUS

Phone: +1 205 579 3531 Email: jannatul.jfh@gmail.com Website: https://jannatul-ferdous.netlify.app

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jannatul-ferdous Address: 711 11th Street, Tuscaloosa, Alabama, 35401

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am an accomplished academic and administrative professional with a strong background in English Language & Literature and Human Resource Development. With experience in student counseling, job placement, and international student affairs, I have successfully guided students in their academic and professional pursuits. My research interests focus on education, women's empowerment, and teaching, leading to published studies on EFL learning. Additionally, I have held leadership roles in academic organizations and social initiatives, demonstrating my commitment to education and community development. Recognized for my achievements in national competitions, I possess strong analytical writing, public speaking, and assessment skills, contributing effectively to academic and institutional excellence.

EDUCATION

• MA in Human Resource Development & Industrial Relations, 2023

Department of Public Administration

JAHANGIRNAGAR UNIVERSITY, Bangladesh

CGPA: 3.53 (Scale 4.00)

• BA Hons. in English Language & Literature: 2021

Department of English,

DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY, Bangladesh

CGPA: 3.42 (Scale 4.00)

RESEARCH INTEREST

• Women Empowerment

• Women Societal & Educational Development

- Feminist pedagogy
- Introspective Techniques

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Analytical writing
- Teaching and Pedagogical Knowledge
- Data Analysis
- Reporting
- Assessment & Evaluation

PUBLICATIONS

- Shuchi, B., **Ferdous, J.**, & Hasan, F. (2024). The Impact of Extracurricular Activities on Learner's Achievement in EFL: A Study at Daffodil International University. *Open Journal of Educational Research*, 4(6), 310–322.https://doi.org/10.31586/ojer.2024.1086
- **Ferdous, J.**, Shuchi, B., & Afrin, M. (2024). Impact of Classroom from the Primary Level of the Acquisition of English as a Second Language in Bangladesh. *Universal Journal of Literature and Linguistics*, 4(1), 83–94. https://doi.org/10.31586/ujll.2024.1122

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

- Developing education pathways for slum and street children
 - Collected data from 18 different slums of Dhaka city and identified possible education pathways for dwelling children.
- English as a second language acquisition teaching method of English Medium schools of Dhaka, Bangladesh

 Conducted survey-based research, interviewing 22 English Medium School teachers on English as a second language acquisition teaching methodology.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- DEPARTMENT OF ENGLISH, DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY (2021)
 - Course: English Language Teaching (ELT)
 - Responsibilities: lesson plan, material preparation, and class conduction
- MOHAMMADPUR GOVERNMENT IDEAL PRIMARY SCHOOL, DHAKA (2018)

Conducted English class of underprivileged slam children

OTHER JOB EXPERIENCES

• DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY (DIU)

Assistant Administrative Officer: November 2021 – May 2024

- Specialized in student counseling and development
- Successfully secured job placements for over 250 students across various industries.
- Organized 6 on campus spot recruitment and 2 Job Fair
- DAFFODIL INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY (DIU)

Student Associate- International Affairs: August 2021 – October 2021

- Counseling international students regarding exchange program
- Successfully communicated with foreign delegates regarding admission of Bangladeshi students

CONFERENCES AND WORKSHOPS

- International Conference on Post-colonial Perspective: Language, Literature, Culture and the Global South, 14-15 Feb 2020
- 1st IML International Language Teaching and Learning Conference, 2017
- Workshop on conflict management, August 2021

AWARDS

- National English Olympiad top finalist among 50,000 students, 2019
- Education waiver of around \$1000 under "newspaper reading project" of Department of English, DIU
- Second runner-up at Presentation Competition on "Road to Corporate-2019" program

LEADERSHIP AND COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

BRITISH COUNCIL, BANGLADESH

Team Leader: January 2021 – June 2021

- Organized social awareness campaign in a community of Dhaka City about "Green Reformation of walls & spaces".
- Reached around 100 families with both physical and virtual medium
- English Literary Club, DIU

Vice President: 2018-2019

- Organized an English Speaking Platform every Thursday to help students become more comfortable with English language speaking.
- Coordinated events on behalf of the Department of English at Daffodil International University.
- Coordinated Cosplay & Drama Fest in several events.